thinking about little girls,
في التفكير حول الفتيات الصغيرات،
which is kind of a weird thing for a grown man in our society to say.
وهذا يبدو شيئا غريبا ليقوله رجل بالغ في مجتمعنا.
But I do. I spend most of my time thinking about little girls,
لكنني بالفعل أمضي معظم وقتي بالتفكير فيهن،
and I think it's primarily because I have one.
وسبب ذلك بشكل رئيسي لأنه لدي طفلة.
This one's mine, and I think you would really like her.
هذه صغيرتي، وأظن حقا أنكم ستحبونها.
She is smart and funny
إنها ذكية ومرحة
and kind to people and a good friend.
و لطيفة مع الناس وصديقة جيدة.
But when I talk about my daughter, the word I find myself saying most
لكن عندما أتكلم حول ابنتي، أجد كلمة واحدة تتردد علي كثيرا
is "athlete."
هي "رياضية".
My kid's athletic.
صغيرتي رياضية.
She is strong and fast
هي قوية و سريعة
and has great balance and good body control.
تملك توازنا ممتازا و تحكما بدنيا جيدا.
She is a three-time, back-to-back-to-back state champion
لقد كانت لثلاث مرات بطلة الولاية تتابع
in Shaolin Kempo.
في الشاولين كمبو.
At nine years old, she is already halfway to a black belt.
في عامها التاسع، كانت قد أمضت نصف الطريق للحصول على الحزام الأسود.
My daughter is athletic.
ابنتي رياضية.
Now, when a man who is six feet two and 265 pounds stands in front of you
الآن، عندما يقف رجل بطول ستة أقدام و يزن 265 باوندا أمامكم
and says his daughter is athletic,
ويقول أن ابنتي رياضية،
you might think that's a reflection of him.
قد يجعلكم تعتقدون أن هذا بفضله.
It is not.
هذا غير صحيح.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
My wife in high school was a two-time all-state soccer player
زوجتي في الثانوية كانت لمرتين بطلة كرة القدم على مستوى الولاية
and a two-time all-state volleyball player,
ولمرتين بطلة الكرة الطائرة على مستوى الولاية،
and I played "Dungeons and Dragons."
بينما أنا كنت ألعب لعبة "حصون و تنانين."
And that is why,
وبسبب هذا،
although my daughter is an athlete,
بالإضافة إلى أن ابنتي رياضية،
she's also a huge nerd, which I love.
هي أيضا متفوقة دراسيا جدا، الأمر الذي أحبه.
She walks around our house in a cloak of flames
تتجول داخل المنزل مرتدية عباءة باللهب
that she made herself.
قامت بصناعتها وحدها.
She sits on the Iron Throne --
تجلس على عرش حديدي --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
even though she has never seen "Game of Thrones,"
رغم أنها لم تشاهد "صراع العروش" مطلقا من قبل،
primarily because we are not the worst parents who ever lived.
بالطبع لأننا لسنا أسوأ الآباء في العالم.
But she knows there's someone called the Mother of Dragons,
لكنها تعرف أنه توجد واحدة تلقب نفسها بأم التنانين،
and she calls herself that and she loves it.
وهكذا تطلق على نفسها وهي تحب هذا.
She's a huge comic book fan.
معجبة كبيرة بكتب الرسوم المتحركة.
Right now, her favorite character is Groot.
حاليا، شخصيتها المفصلة هو جروت.
She loves Groot.
إنها تحب جروت.
She adores The Incredible Hulk.
وتحب أيضا هالك العظيم.
But my daughter really at heart,
لكن شغف ابنتي الحقيقي،
her thing is Star Wars.
حبها هو فيلم حرب النجوم.
My kid is a Jedi.
صغيرتي هي جيداي.
Although some days she's also a Sith,
في بعض الأيام أيضا هي سيث،
which is a choice that I can respect.
وهذا قرار يمكنني احترامه كثيرا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But here's the question that I have to ask.
لكن السؤال الذي أود طرحه،
Why is it that when my daughter dresses up,
لماذا عندما تتقمص ابنتي شخصية ما،
whether it's Groot or The Incredible Hulk,
لا يهم إن كان جروت أو هالك العظيم،
whether it's Obi-Wan Kenobi or Darth Maul,
أو كان أوبي-وان كينوبي أو دارث ماول،
why is every character she dresses up as a boy?
لماذا أي شخصية تتقمصها تكون ذكرا؟
And where are all the female superheroes?
وأين هم الإناث الخارقات ؟
And that is not actually the question,
صراحة هذا ليس السؤال،
because there's plenty of female superheroes.
لأنه هناك العديد من الإناث الخارقات.
My question really is, where is all the female superhero stuff?
سؤالي حقيقة هو، أين هي أشياء الإناث الخارقات؟
Where are the costumes? Where are the toys?
أين هي كل الأزياء؟ أين هي الألعاب؟
Because every day when my daughter plays when she dresses up,
لأنه كل يوم عندما تقوم ابنتي باللعب وتقمص شخصية،
she's learning stuff
تتعلم أشياء جديدة
through a process that, in my own line of work,
عن طريق ما نطلق عليه، في مجال عملي،
as a professor of media studies,
كبروفيسور في دراسات الإعلام،
we refer to as public pedagogy.
البيداغوجية العامة (علم التربية العامة).
That is, it is how societies are taught ideologies.
هذا يعني كيف يتعلم المجتمع الإيديولوجيات.
It's how you learned what it meant to be a man or a woman,
إنها حول كيف تعلمت ما يعني أن تكون رجلا أو امرأة،
what it meant to behave yourself in public,
ماذا يعني التصرف بأدب مع الناس،
what it meant to be a patriot and have good manners.
ماذا يعني أن تكون وطنيا والتحلي بالصفات الجيدة.
It's all the constituent social relations that make us up as a people.
انها تلك العلاقات الاجتماعية المكونة التي تجعل منا أفرادا.
It's, in short, how we learn what we know about other people
إنها باختصار، كيف نتعلم ما نعرفه حول الأناس الآخرين
and about the world.
وحول العالم.
But we live in a 100-percent media-saturated society.
لكننا نعيش في مجتمع متشبع تماما بالإعلام.
What that means is that every single aspect of your human existence
وهذا ما يعني أن أي خاصية تتحلى بها كفرد بشري
outside of your basic bodily functions
خارج نطاق وظائف جسمك الطبيعية
is in some way touched by media.
هي بطريقة ما متأثرة بالإعلام.
From the car that you drive to the food that you eat
من السيارة التي تقودها إلى الطعام الذي تأكله
to the clothes that you wear
إلى الملابس التي ترتديها
to the way you construct your relationships
إلى طريقة بنائك لعلاقاتك
to the very language you use to formulate thought --
إلى اللغة ذاتها التي تستخدمها لصياغة الأفكار--
all of that is in some way mediated.
كل هذا متأثر بطريقة ما بالإعلام.
So the answer in our society
إذن, فالإجابة عن هذا السؤال في مجتمعنا
to how do we learn what we know about other people and about the world
عن كيفية تعلمنا ما نعرفه حول الأشخاص وحول العالم
is largely through media.
هو بالمجمل من خلال الإعلام.
Well, there's a wrinkle in that,
حسنا يوجد مشكل هنا،
in that our society,
ففي مجتمعنا،
media don't simply exist as information distribution technologies and devices.
الإعلام ليس فقط مجرد تكنولوجيات إعلام و إتصال.
They also exist as corporate entities.
بل هو ظاهر أيضا على شكل شركات.
And when the distribution of information is tied to financial gain,
وعندما يتصل نشرالمعلومات بالربح المادي،
there's a problem.
هنا تكمن المشكلة.
How big of a problem?
كم كبيرة هذه المشكلة؟
Well think about this:
حسنا، فكروا في هذا:
in 1983, 90 percent of American media were owned by 50 companies.
في العام 1983، 90 بالمائة من الإعلام الأمريكي كانت تملكه 50 شركة.
In any market, 50 companies doing something is a lot of companies.
في أي سوق، 50 شركة تقوم بشيء ما يعتبر عددا مهما من الشركات.
It's a lot of different worldviews.
إنها كثيرة جدا بالاعتبار العالمي.
In 2015, that number has shrunk to six,
في العام 2015، تقلص هذا الرقم ليصبح ستة فقط،
six companies.
ستة شركات.
They are NBCUniversal Comcast, AOL Time Warner,
هي NBCUniversal Comcast، AOL Time Warner،
the Walt Disney Company, News Corp, Viacom and the CBS Corporation.
والت ديزني، News Corp، Viacom و CBS Corporation
These six companies produce nine out of every 10 movies you watch,
هذه الشركات الستة تنتج تسعة من كل 10 أفلام تشاهدها،
nine out of every 10 television shows, nine out of every 10 songs,
تسعة من كل 10 برامج تلفزيونية، تسعة من كل 10 أغاني تسمعها،
nine out of every 10 books.
تسعة من كل 10 كتب.
So my question to you is,
سؤالي لك إذن كالتالي،
if six companies control 90 percent of American media,
إذا كانت ستة شركات تتحكم في 90 بالمائة من الإعلام الأمريكي،
how much influence do you think they have over what you're allowed to see every day?
ما مقدار التأثيرالذي تملكه برأيك حول ما هو مسموح لك برؤيته كل يوم؟
Because in media studies,
لأنه في الدراسات الإعلامية،
we spend a lot of time saying that media can't tell us what to think,
نحن نقول دائما بأن الإعلام لا يمكنه أن يخبرنا ماذا نفكر،
and they can't; they're terrible at that.
ولا يستطيع فعل هذا، إنه فظيع فيما يتعلق بهذا.
But that's not their job.
لكن هذا ليس الغاية منه.
Media don't tell us what to think.
الإعلام لا يعلمنا بماذا نفكر.
Media tell us what to think about.
الإعلام يرشدنا إلى ماذا نفكر.
They control the conversation,
إنهم يتحكمون بالنقاش،
and in controlling the conversation,
وبالتحكم في النقاش،
they don't have to get you to think what they want you to think.
لا يتعين عليهم دفعك للتفكير فيما يريدونك أن تفكر به.
They'll just get you thinking about the things they want you to think about,
بل يدفعونك فقط للتفكير في الأشياء التي يودونك أن تفكر بها،
and more importantly, not thinking about things they don't want you to think about.
والأهم من هذا، عدم التفكير في الأمور التي لا يريدونك التفكير بها.
They control the conversation.
إنهم يتحكمون بالنقاش.
How does this work in practice?
كيف يقومون بهذا بالواقع؟
Let's just take one of those companies.
فلنأخذ كمثال واحدة من هذه الشركات.
We'll do an easy one.
سوف نختار مثالا سهلا.
Let's talk about the Walt Disney Company for a second.
فلنتكلم حول شركة والت ديزني لوهلة.
The reason why I always pick the Walt Disney Company is this.
السبب الذي يدفعني لاختيار والت ديزني دائما هو.
Is there a single person in this room who has never seen a Disney movie?
هل يوجد شخص هنا في هذه القاعة لم يسبق له مشاهد فيلم من ديزني؟
Look around. Exactly.
أنظروا حولكم. بالضبط.
I picked Disney because they have what we call 100 percent penetration
إخترت ديزني لأنها تملك توغلا تاما
Every single person has been exposed to Disney,
في مجتمعنا.
so it's an easy one for me to use.
كل واحد منا تعرض لديزني.
Since 1937, Disney has made most of its money selling princesses to girls.
لهذا فهي خيار سهل بالنسبة لي لاستخدامه.
It's made a huge chunk of its money.
منذ 1937، ديزني حققت كل أرباحها عن طريق بيع دمى الأميرات للفتيات.
Unless, of course, the princess your daughter is interested in,
لقد شكل مصدر ربح كبير لها.
as my daughter is, is this one.
إلا إذا كانت الأميرة التي تهتم بها ابنتك،
See, in 2012,
مثل ابنتي، هي هذه.
Disney purchased LucasFilm for the sum of four billion dollars,
العام 2012،
and immediately they flooded the Disney stores with Han Solo
ديزني قامت بشراء شركة LucasFilm بمبلغ أربعة مليارات دولار،
and Obi-Wan Kenobi, with Darth Vader and Luke Skywalker and Yoda
ومباشرة قامت بإغراق محلات ديزني بهان صولو
and not Princess Leia.
و أوبي-وان كينوبي مع دارث فايدر لوك سكاي والكر و يودا
Why? Because this princess messes up the public pedagogy
لكن ليس بالأميرة ليا.
for these princesses.
لماذا؟ لأن هذه الأميرة تفسد التربية العامة
So Disney did not put Princess Leia merchandise in the store,
لهذه الأميرات.
and when people went to Disney and said,
إذن، ديزني لم تسوق الأميرة ليا في المحلات،
"Hey, where's all the Princess Leia stuff?"
وعندما ذهب الناس إلى ديزني وقالوا،
Disney said, "We have no intention
"أين هي الأشياء الخاصة بالأميرة ليا؟"
of putting Princess Leia merchandise in the store."
أجابت ديزني، "ليس لدينا أي اهتمام
And fans were angry and they took to Twitter
لتسويق الأميرة ليا في المحلات."
with the hashtag #WeWantLeia.
انزعج المعجبون كثيرا ونقلوا هذا إلى تويتر
And Disney said, "Wait, that's not what we meant.
عن طريق الوسم #نحن_نريد_ليا.
What we meant was,
أجابت ديزني، "لحظة، هذا ليس ما قصدناه.
we don't have any Princess Leia merchandise yet, but we will."
ما قصدناه كان،
And that was in 2012, and it is 2015,
لا نملك أي سلع للأميرة ليا بعد، لكننا سنفعل."
and if you go to the Disney Store, as I recently have,
كان ذلك في العام 2012، والآن العام 2015،
and look for Princess Leia merchandise,
وإن توجهت إلى محل ديزني، ولقد فعلت مؤخرا،
do you know how many Princess Leia items there are in the Disney Store?
وبحثت عن أشياء الأميرة ليا،
Zero, because Disney has no intention of putting Princess Leia in the store.
هل تعلمون كم كان هناك من أشياء الأميرة ليا في محل ديزني؟
And we shouldn't be surprised because we found out that was their policy
صفر، لأن ديزني ليس لديها أي نية لوضع الأميرة ليا في المحلات.
when they bought Marvel in 2009
ولا يجب أن نكون مندهشين لأننا وجدنا أن هذه هي سياستهم
for the sum of 4.5 billion dollars.
عندما قاموا بشراء مارفل العام 2009
Because when you make a lot of money selling princesses to girls,
بمبلغ 4.5 مليار دولار.
you also kind of want to make money from boys.
لأنه عندما تحقق أموالا كثيرة عن طريق بيع الأميرات للفتيات،
And so what better to sell boys than superheroes?
تريد أيضا تحقيق بعض المال من الصبيان.
So now Disney had access to Captain America and to Thor,
وما هو الأفضل مبيعا للصبيان من الأبطال الخارقين؟
The Incredible Hulk,
إذن الآن، ديزني وصلت إلى الكابتن أمريكا وإلى ثور،
and they had access even
هالك العظيم،
to a group of superheroes no one had ever even heard of.
ويمكنها الوصول حتى
That's how good Marvel was at selling superheroes.
لمجموعة من الأبطال الخارقين لم يسمع بهم أحد قط من قبل.
Last year, they released a film called "Guardians of the Galaxy."
هكذا كانت مارفل جيدة جدا في بيع الأبطال الخارقين.
It's a film that absolutely should not work.
العام الماضي، أنتجوا فيلما بعنوان "حماة المجرة."
Nobody knew who they were except for comic book nerds like me.
لقد كان فيلما من المفروض أن لا ينجح تماما.
One of the characters is a talking tree.
لا أحد كان يعرف من هم، باستثناء مهووسي كتب الرسوم مثلي.
One of the characters is an anthropomorphic raccoon.
واحد من الشخصيات كان شجرة متكلمة.
It should not work.
و آخر كان راكونا متجسما.
And they made a killing off of "Guardians of the Galaxy."
كان من المفروض أن لا ينجح.
This character here in the middle, her name is Gamora.
إلا أنهم جنوا الكثير من "حماة المجرة."
She's played by Zoe Saldana,
هذه الشخصية هنا في المنتصف، إسمها غامورا.
and she is strong and smart and fast and fights like a ninja,
لعبت دورها الممثلة زوي سالاندا،
and she is played by a beautiful black woman,
وهي قوية وذكية وسريعة وتقاتل كالنينجا،
and my daughter fell in love with her.
لعبت دورها امرأة جميلة سوداء.
So like any good nerd dad, I went to buy my daughter Gamora stuff,
ووقعت ابنتي في حبها.
and when I got to the store, I learned a very interesting thing.
إذن مثل أي أب طيب مهووس، ذهبت لأشتري لابنتي أشياء غامورا،
If I wanted to buy her a Gamora backpack,
وعندما وصلت للمحل، تعلمت شيئا مثيرا للإهتمام.
well, Gamora's not on it.
إذا أردت أن أشتري لها حقيبة ظهر غامورا،
They probably should have marketed this as "some" of the Guardians of the Galaxy.
حسن، لا يوجد فيها غامورا.
(Laughter)
ربما كان عليهم أن يكتبوا عليها "بعض حماة المجرة".
And if I wanted to buy her a lunchbox, she wasn't on it,
(ضحك)
and if I wanted to buy her a t-shirt,
وإذا أردت أن أشتري لها علبة غداء، لم تكن عليها أيضا،
she wasn't on it.
وإذا أردت أن أشتري لها قميصا،
And as a matter of fact,
لم تكن عليه أيضا.
if I went to the store, as I did,
في الحقيقة،
and looked at the display,
إذا ذهبتُ إلى المحل، مثلما فعلت،
you would find a small picture of Gamora right here,
ونظرت إلى هذا العرض،
but if you look at any of the actual merchandise on that shelf,
سوف تجد صورة صغيرة لغامورا هنا،
Gamora is not on any of it.
لكن إذا نظرت إلى أي من السلع على الرفوف،
Now, I could have taken to Twitter with the hashtag #WheresGamora,
غامورا لا توجد على أي منها.
like millions of fans did across the world,
كان من الممكن أن أتكلم عن هذا في تويتر تحت وسم #أين_غامورا،
but the truth was I wasn't even really that surprised,
مثلما فعل الملايين من المعجبين حول العالم،
because I was there when Disney had released "The Avengers."
لكن الحقيقة أني لم أكن حتى متفاجئا،
And just this year, we got a new Avengers movie, the "Age of Ultron,"
لأنني كنت متواجدا عندما أطلقت ديزني "المنتقمون."
and we were very excited,
وهذا العام فقط, لدينا فيلم جديد للمنتقمين بعنوان "عصر ألترون،"
because there was not one but two female superheroes,
وقد كنا جد متحمسين،
Scarlet Witch and Black Widow.
لأنه لم توجد واحدة فقط بل بطلتين خارقتين،
And we were very excited.
سكارلت ويتش وبلاك ويدوو.
But here's the real thing about this.
و قد كنا جد متحمسين.
Even though Scarlett Johansson,
لكن هذه الحقيقة حول هذا.
who is one of the most popular actresses in America, plays Black Widow,
حتى وإن سكارلت جوهانسن،
and Black Widow is the star
و هي واحدة من أعظم الممثلات في أمريكا لعبت درو بلاك ويدوو،
of not one, not two, but five different Marvel movies,
وبلاك ويدوو" هي البطلة
there is not a single piece of Black Widow merchandise available.
ليس فقط لواحد أو اثنين, لكن خمسة أفلام مارفيل،
Not one.
و ليس هناك قطعة واحدة "لبلاك ويدوو" متواجدة.
And if you go to the Disney store and look for a Black Widow costume,
ولا واحدة.
what you will find, is you will find Captain America and The Incredible Hulk.
وإذا ذهبت إلى محل لديزني وبحثت عن زي بلاك ويدوو،
You will find Iron Man and Thor.
ما ستجده هو زي الكابتن أمريكا وهالك العظيم.
You will even find War Machine,
سوف تجد الرجل الحديدي و ثور.
who isn't even really in the movie that long.
سوف تجد حتى الآلات الحربية،
Who you will not find is Black Widow.
التي لم تكن حتى متواجدة في الفيلم مدة طويلة.
And I could have gone to Twitter with the hashtag, as many people did,
والذي لن تجده هو بلاك ويدوو.
# WheresNatasha.
وكان بإمكاني التكلم عن هذا في تويتر بوسم، مثلما فعل الكثير من الناس،
But I'm tired of doing that.
#أين_ناتاشا.
I'm tired of having to do that.
لكنني سئمت من فعل هذا.
All over the country right now,
أنا سئم من أنني يجب أن أفعل هذا.
there are kids playing with the Cycle Blast Quinjet play set,
في كل أنحاء البلاد الآن،
where Captain America rides a motorcycle out of a moving jet
يوجد أطفال يلعبون بتماثيل Cycle Blast Quinjet
and it's really awesome.
حيث يقفز الكابتن أمريكا من طائرة نفاثة ليقود دراجة نارية
You know how awesome it is?
وهذا حقا رائع.
So awesome that when it happened in the movie,
أتعلمون كم هذا رائع؟
it was Black Widow that did it.
رائع لدرجة أنه لما مرت هذه اللقطة في الفيلم،
Not only has she been erased,
كانت بلاك ويدوو التي فعلتها.
but she has been replaced with a male figure.
لم يتم فقط حذفها،
And so what is this teaching us?
بل وتم استبدالها بشخصية ذكر.
I mean, over the next five years,
إذن ما الذي يعلمنا هذا؟
Disney and Warner Bros. and a bunch of movie studios
أعني، في السنوات الخمس القادمة،
are going to release over 30 feature-length films
شركتا ديزني و وارنر بروس. وبعض استوديوهات انتاج الأفلام
with comic book characters,
سيقومون بإنتاج ما يفوق 30 فيلما روائيا طويلا،
and of those 30 feature-length films,
بالإضافة إلى شخصيات كتب الرسوم،
exactly two of them will have female solo leads.
ومن بين هذه الأفلام الروائية الثلاثين،
Two.
اثنان منها بالضبط سيكونان من بطولة امرأة.
Now, there will be females in the rest of these movies,
اثنان.
but they will be sidekicks, they will be love interests,
حسنا، سوف يكون هناك إناث في بقية الأفلام،
they will be members of teams.
لكنهن سيكن شخصيات جانبية، شخصيات محببة،
They will not be the main character.
سيكن أعضاء من الفرق.
And if what we learn, what we know
لكن لن يكن الشخصيات الأساسية.
about other people and about the world we learn through media,
وإذا كان ما نتعلمه، ما نعرفه
then these companies are teaching my daughter that even if she is strong
بشأن الأشخاص الآخرين وبشأن العالم عن طريق الإعلام،
and smart and fast and fights like a ninja,
فإن هذه الشركات تعلم ابنتي أنه حتى ولو كانت قوية
all four of which are true of her,
وذكية وسريعة وتقاتل مثل النينجا،
it doesn't matter.
وكل هذه الصفات الأربع توجد فيها،
She will either be ignored like Gamora
فهذا لا يهم.
or erased and replaced with a boy
سوف يتم تجاهلها مثل غامورا
like Black Widow.
أو حذفها واستبدالها بصبي
And it's not fair.
مثل بلاك ويدوو.
It's not fair to her and it's not fair to your sons and daughters either.
وهذا ليس عادلا.
But here's the thing:
هذا ليس عادلا لها وليس عادلا لأولادكم وبناتكم أيضا.
I'm raising a little girl, and she has a little tomboy in her,
لكن إليكم الأمر:
which by the way is a terrible thing to call a girl.
أنا أربي طفلة صغيرة، وهي مسترجلة بعض الشيء،
What that basically is saying is, those traits that define you,
وهذا بالمناسبة شيئ فظيع لتقوله لطفلة.
they're not really yours,
هذا يعني أن تلك الحدود التي تحددك أنت،
they're just on loan to you for a little while from boys.
ليست بالحقيقة حدودك،
But do you know how much grief she's going to take in her life
انها فقط لك على سبيل الاعارة لبعض الوقت من الصبيان.
for having a little tomboy in her?
لكن هل تعلمون مقدار التعليقات التي سوف تتلقاها في حياتها
Zero. None.
لأنها مسترجلة بعض الشيئ؟
People will think it's cute.
صفر. لا شيء.
They'll call her feisty, because in our society,
الناس سيعتقدون أنها لطيفة.
adding so-called male traits to girls
سوف ينادونها بالبطل، لأنه في مجتمعنا،
is seen as an upgrade, seen as a bonus.
إضافة صفة ذكورية كهذه إلى الفتيات
I'm not raising a little boy, like Mike.
يعتبر كأنه ترقية، وكأنه مكافأة.
Mike is a little boy in Florida. He's 11 years old,
أنا لست أربي طفلا صغيرا، مثل مايك.
and the thing that he loves most in the world
مايك طفل صغير في فلوريدا. عمره 11 سنة،
is a show called "My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic,"
وأكثر أمر يحبه في هذا العالم
like millions of other children across America.
هو برنامج اسمه "مهري الصغير: الصداقة سحر،"
Now, the show is marketed to girls ages five to nine,
مثل الملايين من الأطفال الآخرين في أمريكا.
but there are millions of boys
الآن، هذا البرنامج يسوق للفتيات بين سن الخامسة والتاسعة،
and grown men
لكن هناك الملايين من الصبيان
who enjoy "My Little Pony: Friendship is Magic."
ورجال بالغون
They have a club.
يستمتعون ببرنامج "مهري الصغير: الصداقة سحر."
They call themselves Bronies,
يملكون ناديا.
pony bros, guys who like ponies.
ويسمون أنفسمهم البرونيز،
I happen to be one of them.
أخوة المهور، الأشخاص الذين يحبون المهور.
And what are Mike and myself
ويصدف أنني واحد منهم.
sissified world of "My Little Pony?"
وما الذين نتعلمه أنا ومايك
Well, they're learning to study hard and to work hard and to party hard
والملايين من الصبيان والرجال من هذا العالم الأنثوي،
and to look good and to feel good
والمخنث من "مهري الصغير؟"
and to do good,
حسنا، تعلمنا أن ندرس بجد وأن نعمل بجد ونحتفل بصخب
and heaven preserve us from teaching these wussified concepts to boys.
أن نبدو رائعين ونشعر بشعور رائع
So the other kids in his neighborhood pick on Mike and they beat him up
وأن نفعل أشياء رائعة،
and they make fun of him,
ولتحمنا السماء أن نعلم هذه المفاهيم المخنثة للصبيان.
and at 11 years old, Mike goes home,
قام أطفال الحي الآخرون بالإمساك بمايك وبضربه
finds a belt, wraps it around his neck,
وقاموا بالإستهزاء به،
and hangs himself from the top bunk of his bed.
وفي سن الحادية عشر،يذهب مايك إلى المنزل،
Because we have developed a society
ليجد حزاما، فيلفه حول عنقه،
in which you would rather be dead as a boy than thought of as liking stuff for girls.
ويشنق نفسه من أعلى سريره.
And that is not Mike's fault. That is our fault.
لأننا قمنا بتطوير مجتمع
We have failed him.
تفضل فيه أن تكون ميتا كصبي على أن تحب أشياء للفتيات.
We have failed our children.
وهذا ليس خطأ مايك. هذا خطأنا.
And we have to do better for them.
لقد خذلناه.
We have to stop making it so that the only female superheroes
لقد خذلنا أولادنا.
appear on shirts that are pink and cut for girls.
وعلينا أن نفعل أفضل من هذا لأجلهم.
We have to stop.
علينا أن نوقف جعل الإناث الخارقات
And when I was putting this together, people said to me,
يظهرن على أقمصة وردية ومخصصة للفتيات.
"Well, that's never going to happen." And I said, "Oh really?"
علينا أن نتوقف.
Because just this year, Target announced
عندما قمت بجمع كل هذه الأفكار، قال الناس لي،
that they were going to stop gendering their toy aisles.
"هذا لن يحصل أبدا." فأجبت، "حقا؟"
They were going to mix it up.
لأنه هذا العام بالتحديد، أعلنت شركة تارجت
Now, before we break our shoulders patting Target on the back,
أنهم سيتوقفون عن تجنيس اللعب.
just this week they released a shirt
سيقومون بخلطها.
in which one of the most iconic scenes in "Star Wars: A New Hope"
الآن، قبل أن نبدأ بمدح تارجت،
where Princess Leia stands up to the Dark Lord of the Sith,
هذا الأسبوع تحديدا قاموا بإطلاق قميص
was released on a t-shirt
فيه واحد من المشاهد المميزة جدا في فيلم "حرب النجوم: أمل جديد"
in which she's mysteriously replaced by Luke.
حيث تقف الأميرة ليا في وجه ملك الظلام،
So let's don't pat ourselves on the back too much.
تم إطلاقه في قميص
Just this week also,
تم استبدالها فيه بغموض بشخصية لوك.
Disney announced it was no longer going to gender its Halloween costumes,
فدعونا لا نفرح كثيرا.
which I say, "Thank you, Disney,
وهذا الأسبوع تحديدا أيضا،
except the only costumes you make are of male superheroes,
أعلنت ديزني أنها لن تقوم بتجنيس أزياء الهالوين مجددا،
so does it matter who you have wearing them?"
وبهذا أقول: "شكرا ديزني،
Just this week, Mattel, who makes Barbie,
إلا أن الأزياء الوحيدة التي تنتجينها هي لأبطال خارقين ذكور،
announced they're going to release a line of DC superhero girls.
فهل يهم من ذا الذي سيرتديها؟"
And the funny thing is,
هذا الأسبوع فقط، ماتل، التي تنتج دمى باربي.
they met with girls
أعلنت أنها سوف تطلق سلسلة من الفتيات الخارقات.
and asked them what they wanted to see in dolls,
والشيء المضحك هو،
and you can see, they have calves
أنهم التقوا بفتيات
and elbows that bend so they can do superhero stuff.
وسألوهن ماذا يردن في هذه الدمى،
And please buy them.
ويمكنكم أن تروا، يملكن سيقانا قوية
And don't just buy them for your daughters,
وأكتافا مشدودة كي يقومن بأشياء خارقة.
buy them for your sons.
وأرجوكم اشتروها.
Because it's important that boys play with and as female superheroes
ولا تشتروها من أجل بناتكم فقط،
just as my daughter plays with and as male superheroes.
اشتروها من أجل أبنائكم.
As a matter of fact, what I would love
لأنه من المهم أن يلعب الصبيان كالإناث الخارقات و بألعابهن
is a world in which every person who goes to the store
مثلما تفعل ابنتي عندما تلعب كالأبطال الخارقين و بألعابهم.
goes with a little flowchart in their head
في الحقيقة، ما أرغب به
of whether or not they should buy this toy for a boy or a girl,
هو عالم يذهب فيه أي أحد إلى المتجر
and it's a real simple flowchart because it only has one question on it.
أن يذهب ولديه مخطط في رأسه
It says, "Is this toy operated with your genitals?"
حول أن يشتري هذه اللعبة لصبي أو فتاة،
(Laughter)
وهو مخطط سهل جدا لأنه يتضمن سؤالا واحدا.
If the answer is yes,
وهو: "هل هذه اللعبة متوافقة مع أعضائك الجنسية ؟"
then that is not a toy for children.
(ضحك)
(Laughter)
إن كان الجواب نعم،
And if the answer is no,
فهذه ليست لعبة للأطفال.
then it's for boys and girls.
(ضحك)
It's really simple.
وإذا كانت الإجابة لا،
Because today is about the future of the future, and in my future,
فهي إذاً للصبيان و الفتيات.
boys and girls are equally respected,
إنه لأمر بسيط حقا.
equally valued, and most importantly, equally represented.
لأنه اليوم نحن نتحدث عن المستقبل البعيد وفي مستقبلي أنا،
Thank you.
الصبيان والفتيات محترمون بنفس الدرجة،
(Applause)
مقدرون بنفس الدرجة، والأكثر أهمية، ممثلون بنفس الدرجة.